Guide to the Vincenzo Beltrone Collection 1924-2017 MS 3029
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Writings, 1930s-ca. 1950; 0.834 Linear feet (2 boxes)
  - Fragments & Poetic Letters, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Manuscript and typescript poems from a binder marked "poems to be read again."
  - Poems by Vincent Beltrone, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Typescript poems with handwritten annotations.
  - Variations on a Theme, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - [Poetry], n.d. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Typescript poems from a binder marked "Poems of Romance" [crossed out] and "Poems to Kate" [crossed out].
  - Carbon copies, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Typescript poems from a binder marked "Carbon Copies / General Poems [crossed out] / Vincenzo di Beltrone."
  - [Lola Montez] (2 folders), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
    The typescript poems in folders 13-14 were housed in the cardboard wrapper of a package of Nekoosa watermarked bond paper. One flap (preserved in box 5, folder 13) is marked "Lola Montez," but it is unclear if there is any connection between the nineteenth-century actress and Beltrone's text. His first poem in English—"Myself"—is in folder 13.
  - General Poems (2 folders), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    Typescripts from a portfolio marked "General Poems." Includes material in Italian and some pieces by Kate Fabian Beltrone (box 6, folder 1). Box 6, folder 2 preserves the portfolio.
  - Italian Poetry (3 folders), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3-5)
    Manuscripts and typescripts from a portfolio marked "Italian Poetry." Box 6, folder 5 preserves the portfolio.
  - [Dramatic dialogue], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Manuscript dialogue between Scypio and Omnis, presumably by Vincenzo Beltrone. Written on verso of stationery from Health Brands Distributors, Liquid Garlic Products, 267 East 2nd Street, New York, NY.
  - The Attic Speaks (2 folders), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    Manuscript and typescript prose sketches from an unfinished work called "The Attic Speaks: A Greenwich Village Diary," including "The Arch," "Nefretiti" [sic], "The Suicide," and "Two Village Ladies."
  - [Prose sketches], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Additional sketches that possibly belong to "The Attic Speaks," including "Madame le Baroness," "The Maestro," "Moses in New York," "My Friend Valdo / The Mad Monk," "Papa Greenberg / The Eccentric Landlord."
- Series IV. Print matter, 1933-1959; 0.417 Linear feet (1 box)
  Series IV contains a mix of published material—mostly poetry books (some in Italian) and poetry journals—that belonged to Vincenzo Beltrone and his widow, the poet Kate Fabian Beltrone. Vincenzo died early in 1950, so anything dating from before then could conceivably have been his.
  Kate was a contributing editor to PEGASUS: The Poetry Quarterly, in which she published her late husband's verse along with her own. A few scattered issues are in box 7, folder 2.
  Series IV also includes two small woodblock printing plate portraits of Beltrone, one of which is reproduced in the 1987 version of Roslyn Bernstein's article, "Alien Enemy M68-279: The Unresolved Case of Vincenzo Beltrone" (box 4, folder 8).
  The material in Series IV is separated by format and ordered chronologically within each folder.
  - Italian poetry and "letterature", 1933-ca. 1949 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Contains four items:
    1. Vincenzo De Simone, La Funtana: Sonetti Siciliani (Milano: Edizione "Siculorum Gymnasium," 1933). Inscribed by the author to Vincenzo Beltrone.
    2. Giuseppe Tusiani, Flora, O Primi Fiori di Poesia [poems] (n.p., ca. 1949). Inscribed by the author to Vincenzo Beltrone, 24 January 1949.
    3. Matteo Teresi, Ai Giovani Figli D'Italia (Rochester, N.Y.: Florence Printing and Publishing, n.d.).
    4. G. B. Angioletti and G. Antonini, Panorama of the Contemporary Italian Letterature (Florence: Vallecchi Publisher, n.d.).
  - Poetry journals and dramatic works, 1937-1959 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Contains five items:
    1. George F. Meyers, Astral Broadcasting Networks: The Sorrows of Lilith in her Adventure with Wotan. A Play in Three Acts—With a Prologue ([New York]: published by the author, 1937). Inscribed by the author to V. Beltrone.
    2. Crescendo [poetry journal], vol. 3 (Autumn 1944). Final issue; merged with Iconograph.
    3. Section Eight [poetry leaflet] (1955).
    4. Talisman 7 [literary journal] (Summer 1955).
    5. Flame [literary journal], vol. 6, no. 3 (Autumn 1959).
  - PEGASUS: The Poetry Quarterly., 1953-1958 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Five issues of PEGASUS: The Poetry Quarterly (originally called PEGASUS: The Poetry Quarterly of Greenwich Village), which ran from 1952 to 1960.
    Kate Fabian Beltrone is listed as financial secretary in the PEGASUS issues from 1953 and 1954. In subsequent issues she is a member of the editorial board.
    1. Vol. 2, no. 4 (Fall 1953)
    2. Vol. 3, no. 1 (Spring 1954); includes Beltrone's "Fantasia" and Kate Fabian Beltrone's "Tranquility."
    3. Issue XII, vol. 3, no. 4 (1955); includes Beltrone's "The Blue Mask" and Kate Fabian Beltrone's "Sunlight on a Tear."
    4. Issue XV, vol. 4, no. 3 (1956); includes Beltrone's "Chanzon Triste" and Kate Fabian Beltrone's "The Spinning Disc."
    5. Issue XVIII, vol. 5, no. 2 (1958); includes Beltrone's "Poem to a Dreamer" and Kate Fabian Beltrone's "Washington Square."
  - Poetry books, 1953-1957 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    1. Francis J. Mathues, Bestiary (New York: William-Frederick Press, 1953); illustrated by Alan Thielker.
    2. Harland Ristau, Slum School (Shelbyville, Ind.: Blue River Press, 1954).
    3. Dixie Allen, Idle Thoughts in Poems (New York: Pageant Press, Inc., 1957).
  - [The Heart in Song] (2 folders), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    Tearsheets of "The Heart in Song" poetry column from the dual-language periodical Il Messaggero [The Messenger], published by the Italian Mission Endowment Fund, Inc., Kansas City, Missouri. The top sheet posthumously profiles Beltrone's life and work, with selections from his poetry. Box 7, folder 5 preserves the portfolio that held these sheets.
  - Printing plates, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Two small printing plate portraits of Vincenzo Beltrone mounted on woodblocks, one of which is reproduced in the 1987 version of Roslyn Bernstein's article, "Alien Enemy M68-279: The Unresolved Case of Vincenzo Beltrone" (box 4, folder 8).